<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vae | Nishant Mishra</title>
    <link>https://mnishant2.github.io/tag/vae/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mnishant2.github.io/tag/vae/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>vae</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© NM 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 13:07:25 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://mnishant2.github.io/media/dab.jpg</url>
      <title>vae</title>
      <link>https://mnishant2.github.io/tag/vae/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative Multimodal Learning for Reconstructing Missing Modality</title>
      <link>https://mnishant2.github.io/project/multimodalvae/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 13:07:25 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mnishant2.github.io/project/multimodalvae/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Multimodal learning with latent space models
has the potential to help learn deeper, more useful
representations that help getting better performance,
even in missing modality scenarios.
In this project we leverage latent space based
model to perform inference and reconstruction
in all missing modality combinations.
We trained a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1802.05335&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Multimodal Variational Auto Encoder&lt;/a&gt;


which uses a product of Experts based inference
network on three different modalities consisting
of MNIST handwritten digit images in
two languages and spoken digit recordings for
our experiments. We trained the model in a
subsampled training paradigm using an ELBO
loss that comprised the modality reconstruction
losses, label cross-entropy loss as well as the
Kullback-Leibler divergence for the latent distribution.
We evaluated the total 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Evidence_lower_bound&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ELBO loss&lt;/a&gt;

, individual
reconstruction losses, classification accuracy
and visual reconstruction outputs as part
of our analysis. We observed encouraging results
both in terms of successful convergence as
well as accurate reconstructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We approached the missing modality reconstruction
and classification based problem using a Multimodal Variational
Autoencoder(MVAE). Our model used a tree like graph where the
different modalities define the observation nodes. It consists
of parallel fully connected encoder and decoder networks
associated with each modality as part of a VAE and a product of experts technique for late fusion of the respective
latent distribution parameters from each encoder to get a
final representation. An additional linear decoder branch
was used for label classification.Each modality has its own
inference network. This model was trained by optimizing
an estimated lower bound (ELBO) on the marginal likelihood
of observed data, i.e reconstructions of the modalities
as well as the classification loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also used a sampling
based training scheme such that for each training example
containing modalities, we obtained the loss for all combinations
of modalities given to the model, this ensured the
learned model generalized to perform well in reconstructing
given any combination set of the modalities.
We used three modalities for experimentation and trained the
model on a MNIST dataset with images in two languages,
Farsi and Kannada as first two modalities and speech utterances
of the MNIST digits as the third modality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The model
performed well in terms of the convergence of ELBO loss,
individual reconstruction losses, classification accuracy as
well as the final visual reconstructions of the modalities. We
also performed various analyses in terms of hyperparameter
tuning, reconstruction under different modality combinations
as well as analysis of disentanglement of representation
property.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
